gulfjobsmarket.com 2014-02-12

# Jobs and News Website in the Gulf and the Middle East: Privacy Policy | Gulf Jobs Market

This privacy policy sets out how we (the Nigel Frank International Limited, trading as Gulf Jobs Market) use and protect any information that you give us through this job board site.

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Please note that privacy policy does not apply to our own or our group companies’ main websites, which have their own group privacy policies.

## Changes to our privacy policy

We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. If we change our privacy policy, we will advise you of changes or updates through means of a notice on our website and we will update this privacy policy accordingly. Continued use of this website or our services after this time will constitute your acceptance of the new policy.

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy commitment, please e-mail us at dpa@nigelfrank.com.

You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 20 June 2013.

## Candidates

We may collect the following information:

  * Name and job title
  * Contact information including email address and telephone number
  * Demographic information such as postcode, preferences, salary and interests
  * Other information relevant helping you find job opportunities (your CV)

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Finding you relevant job opportunities
  * To inform you of job opportunities we believe will be of interest to you
  * Internal record keeping
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services
  * We may periodically send promotional email about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail
  * We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests
  * We may also release information relating to you to regulatory or law enforcement authorities

If you apply for a job advertised on our site you can do so without registering. Our site will record your application against that job but also send out an email to the prospective employer with your CV. You may also wish to register on our site so you can store your CV on our web server and make it searchable by prospective employers. Your CV will then be forwarded to prospective employers automatically if you apply for a specific role. 

## Employers

We may collect the following information:

  * Name and job title
  * Contact information including email address and telephone number
  * Various information about the company you work for (address, telephone number, customer base etc)
  * Demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * Other information relevant to providing you and your company with recruitment services

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Finding you relevant candidates
  * To inform you of good candidates when they become available and we believe will be of interest to you
  * Internal record keeping
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services
  * We may periodically send promotional email about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail
  * We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests
  * We may also release information relating to you to regulatory or law enforcement authorities

Employers can log into the site and search against applications, provided two conditions are met. The first is that the candidate has given permission to open up his or her CV to searching by prospective employers, and the second is that the employer’s subscription package includes CV database access. 

## Job alerts and email updates

To subscribe to job alerts emails, employer-related updates, briefings etc, you will be required to provide your name and email address . We will use your email address to keep you informed of the latest jobs relevant to your skills and/or provide you with industry news. If you no longer wish to receive this information, unsubscribe links are provided in every email. You can also receive job alerts via RSS feeds without the requirement to provide your email address or you can use our smartphone apps to receive job adverts, but to do that, you need to provide us with the registration details required by the app. In some cases you may be invited to provide optional demographic and personal interest information that is used to keep our content as relevant as possible.

New members may receive a welcome e-mail to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Where this is the case we present the option to not receive these types of communications at the point of sign up.

## Site and Service Updates

We also send you site and service announcement updates. Members are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with members to provide requested services and in regard to issues relating to their accounts via e-mail or phone.

## Clear Gifs

We employ a software technology called clear gifs (also known as web beacons/web bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are not tied to users’ personally identifiable information. In addition, we use clear gifs in our HTML-based e-mails to let us know which e-mails have been opened by the recipients . This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. All of our job alerts provide the facility to opt-out.

## Surveys & Contests

From time to time we may ask you for information through surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose any information to us. Information we request may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

## Recommend this site

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for the friend’s name and e-mail address. You must not give us these details unless the friend has given you express permission to share his or her details with us. We will automatically send the friend a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit the site. This information is not stored except for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic, managerial and contractual procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Secure pages of the site, such as the order form, and sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number ) are encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry – SSL. While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. 

All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment.

## Aggregate information about online visitors

We gather information and statistics about all visitors to our website (e.g. which area users access most frequently or which services users access the most). That includes IP addresses (which are not linked to personally identifiable information) and broad demographic information. We only use this kind of data in aggregate form. The information helps us to identify the services most beneficial to our users. It also helps us to continually improve our online services and provide a better overall experience to our users. We may publish some of this information on the website. We may also undertake marketing profiling to help us identify services or jobs which may be of interest to you.

## How we use cookies

We use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit http://www.aboutcookies.org for detailed guidance. 

The list below describe the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. 

In summary, we use cookies for the convenience of visitors. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users in order to enhance the experience on our site. Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to, or control over, these cookies.

Currently we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete the cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, “Private Browsing” in Firefox and Safari.) 

## How to disable Cookies

All modern browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These settings will typically be found in the ‘options’ or ‘preferences’ menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise you should use the ‘Help’ option in your browser for more details. 

## First Party Cookies

These are cookies that are set by this website directly.

Google Analytics: We use Google Analytics to collect information about visitor behaviour on our website. Google Analytics stores information about what pages you visit, how long you are on the site, how you got here and what you click on. This Analytics data is collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of our site and is not tied to personally identifiable information. We therefore do not collect or store your personal information (e.g. your name or address) so this information cannot be used to identify who you are. 

You can find out more about Google’s position on privacy as regards its analytics service at http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html

## Third Party Cookies

These are cookies set on your machine by external websites whose services are used on this site. Cookies of this type are the sharing buttons across the site allow visitors to share content onto social networks. Cookies are currently set by LinkedIn, Twitter, Facebook and Google+. In order to implement these buttons, and connect them to the relevant social networks and external sites, there are scripts from domains outside of our website. You should be aware that these sites are likely to be collecting information about what you are doing all around the internet, including on this website. 

You should check the respective policies of each of these sites to see how exactly they use your information and to find out how to opt out, or delete, such information. 

## Session Cookies

We use a session cookie to remember your log-in details for you. These we deem strictly necessary to the working of the website. If these are disabled then various functionality on the site will be broken, including the ability to log-in. 

## Flash Cookies 

Flash cookies may be used to store user preferences for media player functionality and without them some flash content (such as our interactive map) may not render correctly.

## Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Controlling and retaining your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at dpa@nigelfrank.com.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

If your details change (such as your address), or if you no longer wish to use our service, please contact us and we will correct, update or remove your personal data. Some of our sites offer members an account management facility to change or amend their own records.

We will continue to hold your data with the view to providing future services to you. You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please email us at dpa@nigelfrank.com.

## International transfers

If you apply for a job advertised on this site which is outside the European Economic Area, that will inevitably involve the transfer of your personal data on an international basis. Therefore, by using our website and communicating with us electronically, you acknowledge and agree to us processing your personal data in this way.

## Equal opportunities

We are an equal opportunities employer and a company committed to diversity. As such, all job applicants and members of staff will receive equal treatment and we will not discriminate on grounds of gender, race, ethnic origin, colour, marital status, nationality, national origin, disability, sexual orientation, religion or age.

We may occasionally use information provided by you for the purposes of diversity monitoring as part of our commitment to equal opportunities. This information will be used on an entirely anonymous basis.

## Discussion boards

While we take every precaution to ensure all contributions to discussion boards are factually correct, and not deemed to be untruthful, libellous, defamatory, racist or persecutory, these messages are entered by third parties. All users of the board are presented with a set of house rules before taking part. Our editor will monitor as much as possible and although all users of the site are entitled to their opinion, language on the boards must be clean – contributions containing sexual swear words and slander will be removed. Users will be warned if breaking the house rules. A user who consistently breaks the house rules will be barred from the discussion boards. All users are reminded of copyright – Articles from other websites should be linked to rather than copied in full. Articles from the site may be copied in their entirety for use on the site’s discussion boards. We reserve the right to remove articles without notice or reason.

## Contact

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us at the below address or email dpa@nigelfrank.com.

Chief Data Officer

Nigel Frank International Limited

Metropolitan House,

19-21 Collingwood Street,

Newcastle upon Tyne, 

Tyne and Wear,

NE1 1JE

## Company details

Nigel Frank International Limited

Our registered office is at:

Metropolitan House,

19-21 Collingwood Street,

Newcastle upon Tyne,

Tyne and Wear,

NE1 1JE

UK

Registered in England & Wales with company no 05985779

Registered in the Information Commissioner’s register of data controllers at www.ico.gov.uk with registration number Z9892810

Contact: Chief Data Officer, dpa@nigelfrank.com
